Finding Aid for Wallace Frost papers, ca. 1939-1962
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wallace Frost papers
circa 1939-1962
Frost, Wallace, 1892-1962.
85162 Aa 2; AA microcopy
Detroit area architect. Blueprints of selected buildings, biographical materials, advertising and financial material relating to Pittsfield Village, Ann Arbor, Mich., and photographs.
0.1 linear feet
16 blueprints
1 microfilms
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by the family of Wallace Frost (donor no. 5957 ) in 1976, with a small addition in 1992.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Wallace Frost was born in Union, Pennsylvania and studied architecture with Paul Cret at the University of Pennsylvania. He married Grace Bierer in 1917 and settled in Philadelphia. During World War I, he designed hangars for military installations for the Naval air force at their headquarters in Washington. There he met Detroit architect Albert Kahn, who came frequently to Washington for consultations about government architectural projects. Liking his work, Kahn asked Frost to come to Michigan to work with him. Frost moved in 1919, eventually settling in Birmingham in 1921. The two architects worked in the same office on large projects such as the Detroit Public Library, where Frost handled much of the client relations work for Kahn.
In 1926 Frost set up his own practice consisting mainly of residential work in the Detroit suburbs. He worked in Europe in 1932 and 1933 and worked in Southern California from 1933 to 1938, a period in which there was little new building undertaken in Michigan. He planned numerous residences there and built his own large home in 1936 in Montecito Valley, 12 miles from Santa Barbara. In 1939 he returned to Birmingham and practiced in partnership there until 1961. Frost died in 1962.
The collection consists of original blueprints and microfilm of photographs of buildings designed by Frost largely from the period after 1939. Most of the earlier plans and papers were destroyed by fire in California in 1939. There are also a few folders relating to his interest in Pittsfield Village.
Subjects:
Architects.; Architecture.; Frost, Wallace, 1892-1962.; Pittsfield Village (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Apartment houses.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Schools.; Apartment houses--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Architecture.; Birmingham (Mich.)--Buildings.; Buildings--Michigan--Birmingham.; Buildings--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)--Buildings.; Interiors.; Pittsfield School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Pittsfield Village (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Photographs.
- Miscellaneous papers
  - Biographical materials (Box 1)
  - Pittsfield Village
    - Advertising, 1950s (Box 1)
    - Financial, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Miscellaneous, 1950s (Reel 1)
  - Sadler Residence, Birmingham, Mich. (?), June 8, 1950; 4 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Hagerman Residence, Birmingham, Mich. (?), June 8, 1950; 5 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Frost Studio, Birmingham, Mich., June 8, 1950; 4 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Frost Residence, Birmingham, Mich., June 8, 1950; 1 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Jon's Ranch (Jon Frost house), Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1959; 12 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Fred Blow house, West Los Angeles, 1944; 44 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Pittsfield Village, Ann Arbor, 1953; 8 photographs (Reel 1)
  - C.B. Burdick house, Kalamazoo, 4 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Unknown House, 2 photographs (Reel 1)
  - Album 1
    - Frost House, 404 Bonnie Briar, Birmingham, Mich., 1942; 11 photographs (Reel 1)
    - McDonald House (?), 420 Bonnie Briar, Birmingham, Mich., 1942; 1 photographs (Reel 1)
    - Burlingame House, 436 Bonnie Briar, Birmingham, Mich., 1942; 4 photographs (Reel 1)
    - Murphy-Ellis House, 444 Bonnie Briar, Birmingham, Mich., 1942; 4 photographs (Reel 1)
    - Loose photos from album, one of Burlingame House and three of Murphy-Ellis house (Reel 1)
  - Album 2
    - Mr. & Mrs. Wallace Frost house, Ladera Lane, Montecito, Calif., 46 photographs 27 photos attached, 19 loose (Reel 1)
- Architectural drawings
  - Clarence G. Clohset residence, 1950 (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
  - Sperry residence. Port Huron, Mich., 1949 (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
  - Frank Roby residence. Dunstan Road, Bloomfield Hills, Mich. (Cranbrook Quarton estates), 1955 (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
  - Jeremy T. Ball residence. 1390 Northlawn Ave., Birmingham, Mich., 1951 (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
  - Wilkinson residence. 515 Lake Shore Road, Grosse Pointe Shores, Mich., 1954 (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
  - L.B. Burdick residence. Gull Lake, Yorkville, Mich., 1954; also negative photostat (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
  - MacDonald residence. 420 Bonnie Brier, Birmingham, Mich., 1941 (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
  - C. Conn residence. Riverside Drive, Beverly Hills, Mich., 1949 (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
  - Wallace Frost Studio. Bates St., Birmingham, Mich., 1950 (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
  - G.L. Buhrman residence. Geddes Road, Ann Arbor, Mich., 1950 (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
  - Dr. John Smillie residence. Forest Rd., Barton Hills, Ann Arbor, Mich., 1954 (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
  - Pierson residence. Grosse Pointe Farms, Mich., 1954 (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
  - Pittsfield Rental Housing development. Ann Arbor, Mich., 1943 (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
  - Sober residence. Oxford Rd., Riverside Homes, Lansing, Mich., 1958 (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
  - Charles F. Adams residence. 6139 Dakota Circle, Wing Lake, Mich. (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
  - T.M. Ball residence. Orchard Ridge Rd., Bloomfield Hills, Mich., 1950-1955 (Map-case 1, Folder 5)